Do not display this message again

Close window

       Our Position on Privacy and Data Protection - Maplesoft                     

    #### Powerful math software that is easy to use

    #### Advanced System Level Modeling

    [### Maple T.A. and Möbius](https://www.digitaled.com/)[Looking for Maple T.A. or Möbius?  
    DigitalEd, a Maplesoft technology partner, now offers these products. Learn more.](https://www.digitaled.com/)

    #### Automotive and Aerospace

    #### Robotics

    #### Machine Design & Industrial Automation

    #### Other

Toggle navigation

Our Position on Privacy and Data Protection
===========================================

_Last updated: March 6, 2024_  

Waterloo Maple Inc. (“**Maplesoft**”) takes your privacy seriously. This privacy policy explains what personal information we collect from you as you interact with our products and services, and what we do with this information.

We believe that individuals have the right to be informed about the information being collected about them and about its intended use. Individuals also have the right to review information being retained and the means to update and correct it.  
  
To help you better understand how your personal information is protected at Maplesoft, we are providing you with the following statement describing our practices and policies with respect to the privacy of customers and those who visit our website or use other Maplesoft services (referred to “Users” in the sections below). In the event you terminate your relationship with us, or become an inactive customer, we will continue to adhere to the policies and practices described in this notice.  
  
This Privacy Policy is incorporated into and subject to the terms and conditions of Maplesoft’s terms of use, which are located at: [http://www.maplesoft.com/terms/](http://www.maplesoft.com/terms/).  

**Privacy Policy**  
Maplesoft recognizes that appropriate protection and management of personal information is critical and is responsible for any personal information in its possession or custody. We have adopted the following privacy principles for the protection of the personal information of Users.

1. Maplesoft will provide Users with easily understood information about its policies regarding the collection, use and disclosure of personal information.
2. Maplesoft will limit the collection and use of personal information to that which is needed for valid business purposes, or to comply with applicable law, and any such data will be obtained only by lawful and fair means.
3. Maplesoft will only collect personal data with the explicit consent of the User.
4. The User may withdraw their consent and/or request Maplesoft to erase their personal data at any time by contacting Maplesoft’s privacy officer, or, if they have a Maplesoft account (created by the User to access certain products and services), by [asking Maplesoft to delete their Maplesoft account](https://www.maplesoft.com/privacy/delete-account/).
5. Maplesoft will strive to maintain the accuracy of personal information, including establishing mechanisms allowing Users to have the opportunity to review and correct their personal information.
6. Users may request a copy of their personal data at any time by contacting Maplesoft’s privacy officer. A monetary charge may apply.
7. Maplesoft will not disclose personal information to third parties, unless:

* The User requests it;
* The data is provided to help complete a user-initiated transaction;
* The disclosure is required by law;
* The User has been informed about the possibility of such disclosure and has agreed to it;
* The User has purchased a third party product. For these purchases, User contact information will be provided to the third party product developer in order for them to fulfill their support and service obligations to the User; or
* Where the User is a resident of a jurisdiction other than Canada or the United States, Maplesoft may disclose personal information to the Maplesoft office located in the jurisdiction where the User resides. Please visit [http://www.maplesoft.com/contact/](http://www.maplesoft.com/contact/) to view our global office locations.
* Where the User is a resident of a jurisdiction in which Maplesoft does not have offices, Maplesoft may disclose personal information to our authorized third-party partners located in the jurisdiction where the User resides.
* The transfer of personal information is required to process and manage a User’s request and/or account. Third parties may include: Salesforce, RevenueCat, 6sense, Microsoft, Amazon AWS, Eventbrite, SurveyMonkey, Mailchimp, and JIRA.

9. Maplesoft uses contractual or other means to provide protection for the personally identifiable information that is disclosed third parties.
10. Maplesoft has measures in place to protect against the loss or theft of personal information and will notify users within 72 hours of becoming aware of any data breach.
11. Maplesoft may share personal information gathered through the Services and amongst our corporate parents (including, without limitation, Cybernet Systems Co., LTD.), subsidiaries, affiliates or divisions for internal business purposes in accordance with this Privacy Policy. If Maplesoft shares your information within its corporate family, we will ensure that your information continues to be used only in accordance with this Privacy Policy and your expressed choices.

**Maplesoft Web Sites and Services**  
When you are visiting our web site or using our web-based services, we want you to feel secure that Maplesoft is respecting your privacy. The only private information we have about you is the information you choose to give us by filling out a form or an order.  
  
Our web sites use cookies. A cookie is a piece of data that identifies you as a unique user. Maplesoft uses this information to better serve all visitors as we improve the content and design of the services, and to enhance the convenience of using the services by reducing redundant information entry for Users.  
  
The default setting on most web browsers is to accept cookies. You can change this setting to refuse any cookie, or to be prompted when a cookie is being sent. Please note, however, that some areas and features of our services will not function properly if you refuse cookies.

If you are logged in to your Maplesoft account, we collect data about your interactions with Maplesoft web sites and services. This information could include your posts on our user forums, the applications you upload or download on our application sharing sites, your activities on our web store, and which pages on our web sites you visit. We collect this information to provide services such as awarding badges and reputation points on MaplePrimes, to improve our web sites, and to analyze engagement with our audience.

If you are not logged in to your account when you interact with our web site, any data we collect will not be associated with you. However, note that functionality of some Maplesoft services will be restricted if you are not logged in. For example, if you are not logged in, you cannot post to a user forum, upload an application, or access private files in the MapleCloud.

**Email Communications**

Maplesoft operates multiple commercial subscription-based email lists that interested parties can opt-in or opt-out of at any time from the email management area of the Maplesoft web site.  
  
From time to time, Maplesoft may create new subscription-based commercial email lists and may pre-populate these lists with existing Maplesoft email list subscribers, based on subscriber profiles. If you are not already a Maplesoft email subscriber, you will not be added to any newly created Maplesoft email lists.  
  
If you are a Maplesoft customer, and/or you have communicated with Maplesoft recently, you may periodically receive emails from Maplesoft staff or from a Maplesoft email account ending with @maplesoft.com, including emails such as new product updates, security updates, technical updates, customer service updates, and other commercial email communications considered relevant to you, based on your customer or contact profile.  
  
If you would prefer to never receive commercial emails from Maplesoft, you have the option to remove yourself from all present and future email lists by [globally unsubscribing from all communications](https://www.maplesoft.com/subscribers/global_unsubscribe.aspx). You may still subscribe to any Maplesoft email list after globally unsubscribing, and by doing so you will be removed from the global unsubscribe list and put on the list(s) that you subscribe to.  
  
Emails verifying opt-in and opt-out requests are automatically sent to the recipient after each email subscription update.

**Products**  
Our software products require you to activate your license. Activation requires a one-time exchange of information between your computer and Maplesoft. We collect contact information that we use for customer service purposes, such as sending out notifications of software maintenance updates. We also collect basic, non-identifying system information that is used to activate your product. This information also enables us to help you in the future if you have problems with your license. It may also be used for other customer service or development purposes, such as identifying customers who may be subject to problems specific to a single platform, or identifying trends in platform usage.

Software piracy is illegal and Maplesoft reserves the right to take all legal steps to stop piracy of their products and pursue those who take part in these activities. As part of these anti-piracy efforts, our software may contain security mechanisms intended to detect the installation or use of illegal copies of the Software. If an illegal copy is detected, the product may collect and transmit network, device, usage, user, and other data relating to the installation or use of those illegal copies, to Maplesoft and/or their agents. Such data may include, but is not limited to, host name, username, device ID, IP address, Wi-Fi access point information, email address, and information about usage of the software. Maplesoft and/or their agents may use this information to identify and contact users of illegal copies of the Software in order to bring them into license compliance. This data collection is not performed on the users of legally licensed software from Maplesoft and its authorized distributors.

**Maple**

When you use the _AI Formula Assistant_ feature or the _NaturalLanguage_ package in Maple, the text and expressions you enter into the Assistant or by using package commands are sent to a 3rd party for processing. The 3rd party does not receive any information about you other than what you choose to enter. The content you send is only used to process your query. It is not used to train their models or improve their products and services, and the input and output are not retained long-term. Details about the 3rd party’s privacy and security policies relevant to its use in Maple are covered by the _API Platform_ information in the [OpenAI Enterprise Privacy Policy](https://openai.com/enterprise-privacy). Maplesoft stores the inputs/outputs from queries in order to shorten response times for duplicate requests. The stored information is not associated with you in any way. Maplesoft may also use this information for development purposes, such as analyzing usage and quality of results, to help inform future enhancements.

**Maple Calculator Mobile App**

When you take a picture using the Maple Calculator, that image is transmitted to Maplesoft and to a third party server, where the image is automatically analyzed so the mathematical expression can be extracted. Maplesoft will store the images you send for development purposes, such as regression testing and analyzing usage to help inform future enhancements. If you are logged into your Maplesoft account when you take a picture, this image will be associated with you. The third party does not receive any information about the sender, and the images they process are immediately deleted.

If you report a bug through the app and you are logged into your Maplesoft account at that time, this bug report will be associated with you. If the problem involves pictures taken using the app, the image(s) you took and their mathematical interpretation are sent to Maplesoft for analysis, and may be shared with a third party for further investigation. Your identity will not be shared with a third party.

The app collects usage and system information, which will be associated with your Maplesoft account if you are logged in. This data is used for development purposes, such as identifying areas for improvement and determining platform trends.

**Maple Learn**

When you use Maple Learn, the system collects basic usage information, which will be associated with your Maplesoft account if you are logged in at the time. This data is used for development purposes, such as identifying areas for improvement and determining platform and browser trends.

If you report a bug through Maple Learn and are logged into your Maplesoft account at that time, this bug report will be associated with you.

**Safeguarding Security**  
Maplesoft will take appropriate steps to ensure that personal information is protected from unauthorized access and disclosure, including limited access to such data only to those employees with a business need to know. Maplesoft will apply these principles regardless of the specific technologies employed for data collection and use.

**GDPR**  
Maplesoft has processes and policies in place in order to ensure complete compliance with the EU General Data Protection Regulation. [See our GDPR statement for details](https://www.maplesoft.com/GDPR/).

**FERPA**  
Maplesoft has reviewed the requirements of the [Family Education Rights and Privacy Act (FERPA)](https://ed.gov/policy/gen/guid/fpco/ferpa/index.html), and we have identified nothing in any Maplesoft product or service that could prevent or impede a school from complying with the FERPA requirements.

**PIPEDA**  
Maplesoft has processes and policies in place in order to ensure complete compliance with the [Personal Information Protection and Electronic Documents Act (PIPEDA)](https://www.priv.gc.ca/en/privacy-topics/privacy-laws-in-canada/the-personal-information-protection-and-electronic-documents-act-pipeda/) of Canada.

**PIPL**  
Maplesoft has processes and policies in place in order to ensure complete compliance with China’s Personal Information Protection Law.

**Contact Information**  
To ask questions or express concerns, please contact our Privacy Officer by email at [privacy@maplesoft.com](mailto:privacy@maplesoft.com), or by postal mail at: Maplesoft’s Privacy Officer, 615 Kumpf Drive, Waterloo, ON, Canada, N2V1K8. The Privacy Officer will investigate any complaints that concern our compliance with this privacy policy.

**Read More:** [Maplesoft's Corporate Social Responsibility Program and Policy](https://www.maplesoft.com/company/about/social-responsibility-policy.aspx)

**Related Resources**

Maplesoft™, a subsidiary of Cybernet Systems Co. Ltd. in Japan, is the leading provider of high-performance software tools for engineering, science, and mathematics. Its product suite reflects the philosophy that given great tools, people can do great things.  
  
[Learn more about Maplesoft](https://www.maplesoft.com/company/about/).

615 Kumpf Drive  
Waterloo, ON Canada  
N2V 1K8  

1-800-267-6583

Community

Quick Links

Maplesoft E-Mail Lists

_•_

_•_

Maplesoft Membership

**Language:**   [English](https://www.maplesoft.com/privacy/index.aspx)  |  [Français](https://fr.maplesoft.com/privacy/index.aspx?L=F)  |  [Deutsch](https://de.maplesoft.com/privacy/index.aspx?L=G)  |  [日本語](https://jp.maplesoft.com/privacy/index.aspx?L=J)  |  [简体中文](https://cn.maplesoft.com/privacy/index.aspx?L=C)

© Maplesoft, a division of Waterloo Maple Inc., 2024.  • [Terms of Use](https://www.maplesoft.com/terms/) | [Privacy](https://www.maplesoft.com/privacy/) | [Consent Preferences](#) | [Trademarks](https://www.maplesoft.com/trademark/) | [Site Map](https://www.maplesoft.com/site-map/)

×

WeChat
